Hello and welcome to your easy English, where we have easy conversations to help you with your listening skills and learn new vocabulary I'm Beckcker and I'm Neil
If you'd like to see a video version of this podcast you can find it on our website atbblearningenglish.com. the video has subtitles which can help you learn.
Hi Neil, how are you doing today I'm good Thank you I feel great because I just ate a bananaum yeah I saw you you started off your day quite healthily
This morning I also had a banana Yes I saw you eating your banana and I thought I'm going to eat a banana really yes,
Bananas are delicious and today we are actually talking about fruit We are yes, and I love eating fruit me too what kind of fruit do you.
Oh, besides bananas, I really love berries and I like green apples.
U and red grapes, I like lots of fruit How about you Yeah, I really like fruit, I try to eat fruit every day and like you, I like apples.
But not just green ones, the red ones, I like those two, and oranges and I like frozen berries at breakfast.
So you mentioned oranges can be a little sweet, but they're actually more sour, aren't they.
Yeah, sour or sharp, sharp.
Yeah, Yeah, that's the taste that you get from.
Fruit like oranges and more so with lemons or limes.
These are called citrus fruit.
Yeah, citrus fruit.
They have a more of a sour taste.
Yeah, if you bite into a lemon.
That's sour yeah, the face that you make Yeah when you bite into something citrus yeah,
Do you prefer sweetf or sour fruit Yeah, I like sweet fruit and probably I like.
Fruit when it's ripe okay, what does that mean ripe, it means that it's ready to eat it's at its sweetest usually probably quite juicy
If fruit is juicy.
It means juice comes from it and juice is liquid watery.
And it's, if it's ripe, it's just before.
It goes bad or goes off, right, I see, so if we're thinking about bananas for example.
A green coloured banana perhaps isn't ready to eat it's not ripe like a yellow banana Yeah, like a yellow one with sort of brown bits on it that's a ripe banana
Yeah they're a bit too sweet for me I kind of like.
That middle yeah, like yellow bananas How about dried fruit, Do you like dried fruit Oh, I'm glad you asked yes, I really like dried fruit, so I will often.
Have raisins so raisins are dried grapes and dried means that it doesn't have any of that juice or liquid So becca
Here is a really important and interesting question.
If you could only eat one fruit for the rest of your life, which would you choose oh that is a very difficult question we've talked a lot about the fruit that we love.
But probably bananas because I do eat them every day, it feels quite strange to not eat a banana every day for me
And also I really enjoy banana bread.
And dried bananas, I completely forgot about those they're really tasty so yeah there's lots of things you can do with bananas probably those How about you what fruit
Would you choose I think maybe it sounds boring?
But the apple is the perfect snack.
You always feel good after an apple and it makes a fantastic noise when you bite into an apple, that noise is called a crunch and it's a very.
It's a very nice sound it is a nice sound and so we can describe apples as being crunchy that's the adjective yeah.
Okay, it's time to recap the vocabulary that we've learned and we'll start with sour and that is the taste, for example, in lemon or in vinegar.
It's not very sweet citrus fruits for example, like grapefruit, oranges, limes,
They are very sour We use the word ripe ripe describes fruit, which is ready to eat.
We also had juicy and that's an adjective to describe something that has juice or liquid, so for example a juicy fruit like strawberry when you bite into
It juice will come out of it.
We also heard about dried fruit, dried fruit has had all of the juice taken out of it, sometimes by the sun, so for example, raisins are dried fruit.
That's it for this week's episode of Real Ey English, you can find a free worksheet on our website to test what you've learned from this episode that's@bbclearningenglish.com. .
And we'll be back next week with another episode of Real Ey English, join us then goodbye for now, bye.